A world inside the computer where man has never been. Never before now.
Tron is a science fiction, action, adventure film directed by Steven Lisberger.
When brilliant video game maker Flynn hacks the mainframe of his ex-employer, he is beamed inside
an astonishing digital world and becomes part of the very game he is designing.
In his mission through cyberspace, Flynn matches wits with a maniacal Master Control Program and teams
up with Tron, a security measure created to bring balance to the digital environment.
Kevin Flynn / Clu, played by Jeff Bridges.
Alan Bradley / Tron, played by Bruce Boxleitner.
Ed Dillinger / Sark, played by David Warner.
Lora / Yori, played by Cindy Morgan.
Dr. Walter Gibbs / Dumont, played by Barnard Hughes.
Ram, played by Dan Shor.
Tron is a 1982 American science fiction action adventure film written and directed
by Steven Lisberger from a story he co-wrote with Bonnie MacBird.
The film stars Jeff Bridges as Kevin Flynn, a computer programmer and video game developer who is transported inside the
software world of a mainframe computer where he interacts with anthropomorphic programs in his attempt to escape.
It also stars Bruce Boxleitner (in the eponymous role),
David Warner, Cindy Morgan, and Barnard Hughes.
Tron was one of cinema's earliest films to use
extensive computer-generated imagery (CGI).
The inspiration for Tron dates back to 1976, when Lisberger
became intrigued with video games after seeing Pong.
He and producer Donald Kushner set up an animation studio to develop
Tron with the intention of making it an animated film.
To promote the studio itself, Lisberger and his team created a 30-second
animation featuring the first appearance of the title character.
Eventually, Lisberger decided to include live-action elements with both
backlit and computer animation for the actual feature-length film.
Various studios had rejected the storyboards for the film before Walt
Disney Productions agreed to finance and distribute Tron.
There, backlit animation was finally combined with the 2D
computer animation and the live-action footage.
Tron was released on July 9, 1982.
The film was a moderate success at the box office, and received mixed reviews from critics, who praised
its groundbreaking visuals and acting but criticized its storyline as being incoherent.
Tron received nominations for Best Costume Design by Elois Jenssen and Rosanna Norton and Best
Sound by Michael, Bob, and Lee Minkler and Jim La Rue at the 55th Academy Awards.
It was however disqualified from the Best Visual Effects category because at the time the Academy of
Motion Picture Arts and Sciences felt that using computer animation was "cheating".
Tron spawned multiple video games (including an arcade tie-in released shortly after the film)
and, as it became a cult film, a multimedia franchise including comic books.
A sequel titled Tron: Legacy, directed by Joseph Kosinski, was released in 2010, with
Bridges and Boxleitner reprising their roles and Lisberger acting as producer.
A commercial success, it was followed by the Disney XD animated
series Tron: Uprising in 2012, set between the two films.
A third installment, Tron: Ares, was released on October 10, 2025, and also
featured the continued involvement of Bridges and Lisberger.
The film explores themes of hacker, virtual reality,
dystopia, simulation, super computer.
The tone is thought_provoking.